scandpipes.com 2019-08-04

# Privacy Policy - Scandpipes

**We use the following information when shopping at scandpipes.com** :  
Name  
Address  
Phone  
Email address  
\- as well as the IP address from which the purchase is made.

When **paying by credit card** at scandpipes.com, payment is made through a secure connection that ensures that your payment information is unavailable to unauthorised persons.

We register and disclose the personal information necessary to deliver the item to you.  
The personal data are registered at scandpipes.com (and stored for five years after which the information is deleted).

**We collaborate** with a number of companies that store and process data. Companies only deal with information on our behalf and may not use them for their own purposes.

We only collaborate with companies in the EU or in countries that can provide your information with adequate protection.

**You are entitled to know** what information we are processing about you.  
If you believe the information is inaccurate, you are entitled to correct them.  
You are entitled to delete your personal data if they are no longer necessary for the purpose for which we would use them.  
In addition, you have the right to receive the data we store in digital form.  
You can contact us if you believe your personal data is being processed in violation of the law.

**You can write to us** at: [info@scandpipes.com](mailto:info@scandpipes.com)

It is important for us that you feel comfortable shopping at scandpipes.com.  
Scandpipes operates and is data manager for the website  scandpipes.com.  
We comply with all the rules of the Personal Data Act and in the European General Data Protection Regulation 2018.

Scandpipes generally does not store your personal information. This will only happen if Scandpipes is required to do so under applicable legislation.

**Newsletters**  
Scandpipes issues newsletters via YMLP.com. The newsletter system is a "Permission-based" e-mail service that requires specific permission from the subscriber.  
Interactions with YMLP's features are governed by YMLP's Privacy Policy.  
You can unsubscribe from our newsletter (which will delete your data) or you can edit your data via link in our newsletter.

**Cookies**  
scandpipes.com uses the following cookies:  
Session Cookie ID (session cookie)  
Cookie Name: "PHPSESSID"  
Cookie's life: until the browser closes  
Cookies feature: Remember sessions id (which web server uses to connect the visitor with session for shopping cart, country selection, customer login, etc.).

Cookie to remember log in  
Cookien's name: "user"  
Cookie's life: 30 days  
Cookies feature: Remember login information

Cookie for cookie box  
Cookie Name: "cc_cookie_accept"  
Cookie's life span: 12 months.  
Cookies feature: Remember cookies are approved

scandpipes.com uses cookies for page functions, statistics and marketing. By using our web-shop you agree to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file asking for permission to place on your computer's hard drive. Most browsers allow cookies as a default setting. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual by recognising your settings.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually update your browser settings to reject cookies.

A cookie does not allow access to your computer or any other personal information, in addition to the data that you may choose to share with us.

3rd party cookies:  
scandpipes.com uses cookies from external providers.  
3rd party cookies are hosted by that third party and your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the companies that provide these.

scandpipes.com uses cookies from the 3rd party providers below:

Google - Google Analytics:  
Used for statistical, analytical, and marketing purposes (to offer advertisements relevant to you).  
You can opt out of saving cookies with marketing functionality, but note that this does not mean that you will completely avoid being exposed to advertisements. You will continue to receive generic announcements.  
You can opt out of advertising cookies here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
